

# CONTACT

- +27 81 737 8274
- ✓ kirstensuther@gmail.com
- 24 Villa Anadia Bergsig Street Sandbaai Hermanus 7200

# EDUCATION

2017 - 2021

#### **HERMANUS HIGH SCHOOL**

- NSC Bachelors Pass
- GPA: 85.26%

# 2022 - 2024

#### **UNIVERSITY OF CAPE TOWN**

- BSc Computer Science
- GPA: 72.8%

## **LANGUAGES**

English	0-0-0-0	excellent
Afrikaans	0-0-0-0	good
Python	0-0-0-0	excellent
Java	0-0-0-0	excellent
R	0-0-0-0	excellent
SQL	0-0-0-0	good
HTML	0-0-0-0	good
CSS	0-0-0-0	good
C++	0-0-0-0	good
Delphi	0-0-0-0	good

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Critical Thinking
- Effective Communication
- Leadership
- Problem solving
- Data visualization
- Cooperation
- Creative

# KIRSTEN SUTHERLAND

# FINAL YEAR BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE

## **PROFILE**

I am passionate about science, data analytics and programming and would like to use my knowledge and experience in the fields I am studying to positively impact the world around me. Analysing data to find patterns has become a great fascination of mine as well as using those patterns to build systems that can help others. My love for this has grown through studying machine learning and doing a 3 month internship at a Fintech company. I am resilient and refuse to ever give up on my goals.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Fintech Intern

#### Momint

20/11/2023 - 20/02/2024

- Assisted in developing blog content to promote the company to potential clients.
- Developed monthly emails to be sent to existing clients.
- Passed a technical exam, building a student management system Angular app HTML, CSS, TypeScript to perform CRUD operations on a MongoDB database through the development of effective API calls.
- Assisted the developer team on a sprint cycle.
- Made modifications to the front end of a website using WordPress.
- Built both the front end and back end to retrieve and display data from a MongoDB database.

# Student 2022- 2024

#### University of Cape Town

- Built and maintained strong relationships with my fellow students.
- Enrolled in a Financial management course to become more proficient in finances, achieving 79% in the course.
- Furthered my interest in programming and statistics by taking a Machine Learning course, allowing me to learn C++ and various Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning algorithms.
- Enhanced my data analytical skills through taking 1st, 2nd and 3rd year statistics courses.
- Contributed as Communications Lead in our final year Computer Science Capstone project. Tasked with building and Interactive BPE Tokenizer, I built both the BPE Training and BPE Tokenization algorithms for our Capstone Team.

### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

#### **Scouting Patrol Leader**

2018 - 2020

- Dedicated and responsible Student Leader at Hermanus Primary School
- Scout Patrol leader for 3 years: Devoted to improving and developing my patrol
  members in all aspects as well as organising and leading numerous hikes, camps
  and other activities in addition to leading patrols on competitions.
- Chairperson for the Court of Honour for 2 years: The troops Patrol Leaders working alongside the adult Troop Scouters to manage the troop's affairs.

#### **UCT Residence House Committee**

2023

- Organised and led many large scale events to make all residents feel included. (i.e. Alumni Event, formal, orientation week activities)
- Managed and lead a magazine team to produce the 2023 edition of the 2023 residence magazine.